I will do a
traditional preparation in meditation
tomorrow if you want to record it you
can put your phones here
next to each other on the stage and then you can
use it for a few days and
my plan is that this will be the last time
I will conduct the meditation dance
podalo hari this week and next
time we will do something new and this can be
said to be the last review of this meditation and
then you should add this imitation
your tools and start teaching this
meditation to other people and then you will be
ready to move on to a new meditation and so I will
start with the
hands we can arrange them as you
want there is a big problem with
meditation
[music]
eyes all eyes are closed and it doesn't matter how
good you look no one is looking at you
anyway I hope so
just make it so that you are comfortable
sometimes it is comfortable for me to sit like this
sometimes it is more comfortable for me to sit like this sometimes my
hands fall asleep and they are somewhere in the middle there is
this cold I will put my right hand in my
left hand and then I and then it
touches the body and it seems to you I am
flying you are warmer during three years were
three yes we did meditations there were
places where it would not be  there was no
electricity, it was very cold, and then
you definitely do it in this position to feel
warmer.
Meditation is a very personal thing, and you
do exactly what you feel
comfortable in. If you have the right karma, it doesn't
matter how you sit. I had a friend in a
monastery who always meditated with his
legs down. Everyone was saying
he was crazy. One day, we had a debate
competition with another
monastery
[music].
He was sitting with his
legs down, and he defended me
during the debate, and he defended
our monastery during meditation, and
he began to win during the debate,
defeat others. There were three of us,
this is the Alamo Pincha monastery,
and he really just crushed the
opposing side. We all made
mistakes because he
meditated with his hands down when he
studied. He listened to
rock 'n' roll music, it was forbidden, he listened to
music illegally, but he simply
crushed all those opponents, and then
both of them got upset, and he is the greatest
tantric teacher, master.  he is a
geisha teacher that day and he came and started
attacking during the debate our our
monk this is when the coach
starts to urge the players during the game
and our monk continued continued and he
defeated them in disputes and the old abbot has
such a shop and who is known for such
starts nodding his head this is
proof that you can
meditate in any pose letting go of your hands in
fact it doesn't matter what in
fact menace is that you have the
right seeds for meditation seeds
for good meditation this means you
start planting them a week before
meditation and be very attentive to the
feelings of other people don't say anything
that can upset the feelings of other
people
be very careful careful with
what you say to other people and
thereby you bring their minds to peace and
every time you do this you
plant the seeds for good calm
meditation this is the real secret of good
meditation it's not your hands like a pen
your meditation comes from your seeds
well we begin so
place your hands how you want grab
them turn your palm down how you want
but I will not do this and then like
many people who  I concentrate
too, their face becomes very
tense, I saw how I saw myself
playing the sitar, I saw what kind of
angry face I had on my PC,
it was so tense because my mind was strained,
so please, once labs, your face
when I was in Paris last month, we
went to see the Mona Lisa and she has the
perfect smile for meditation, fabric,
light smile, try, can't your
forehead
and relax your eyelids,
hey, relax your fingers, it's very
good if you can pull yours in a little
and hold it a little,
and
it's much easier to do if you haven't
overeaten,
and if you can also pull your stomach
in, it's very good and a little behind and you
can twist your lower back forward a little
and try not to
strain your face, you can bring
your shoulder blades together behind them and straighten your
chest, and it will be easier to do, and
today, move your hands a little closer to
you
from your knee, now focus on your
breathing,
watch your breathing and  Meditation
Dance 2
We immediately focus on certain
noises in the room. This could be the
sound of the refrigerator in your house. This could
be the sound of the air conditioners in this room.
If you live in Lada Ari or
Mexico City, the sound of traffic is very helpful.
Usually, that noise
is an obstacle. In Dance 2, we
use them to begin the meditation. So
let's focus ours on these external
noises.
Let's focus on quieter
sounds. If you are alone in your room, your
apartment, and if it is early in the morning, for example,
[music],
you can listen to the sound of
your heartbeat in your ears.
If this is also the case, but if it is already late in
the morning like today, you can
focus on the feeling of
your heartbeat. Let's focus.
Let's go deeper into the silence and
focus on the feeling of
your heartbeat. The play of your chest.
Let's go even deeper into the silence.
Golden, que si rui, we
go inside your heart.
Place your heart. Inside your heart, it is
not some kind of disorder.
Place what is inside your heart.  A
beautiful room, a very cool place
for meditation, very nice, but the walls
of this room are yours, these are the walls of your
heart, and they are beating,
let's go deeper, silence
[music]
imagine that inside your heart,
beautiful apartments, in these apartments
there is an inner room that is even quieter
[music]
go there to the inner room where it is even
quieter, the
walls are still beating, but this sound
seems very far away, you
hear it slightly from afar,
now imagine the following: a small
piece of sugar, and you dip your finger
into this piece of sugar, you
take out a small piece of sugar on the
tip of your finger in a sugar bowl, and imagine that you
want to meditate inside this
small piece of sugar, so
squeeze yours,
it becomes smaller and smaller, you
open a small door into this
small piece of sugar, and you enter, and
inside, you are surprised that this is
actually a very cool, large
space, a small piece of sugar, you
begin to see, meditate on a
small piece of sugar,
this super quiet heart beats far away, you
no longer hear it,
and so inside this small piece of
sugar,
imagine the
Pacific Ocean  it's very amazing
that inside a small piece of sugar
there is water and an ocean and in the middle of
this ocean one drop of rain falls on the
calm quiet surface of the ocean and
thus waves begin in different
directions and these waves begin in the middle of
this ocean and begin to spread in
the direction of California Mexico China in
the direction of Malaysia and you follow
these waves with your mind slowly
crossing the entire Pacific Ocean and your mind
expands like this ocean inside
a small piece of sugar
now imagine the sky blue sky as
huge as the ocean itself and all this is
inside a money piece of sugar
your mind becomes as wide as
high goes to the height and
width as the ocean and the sky expand in
all directions
let's go even deeper into silence at
each stage we go deeper and
deeper into silence
and now let's try to distinguish our
thoughts like we turn on or off the light
[music]
when I dacha until three trying to
turn off all your thoughts and you or almost a
tavern for a very short time
then some thoughts will try to
speak again two
catch these thoughts and turn off like a light
Be akhra
guards who protects the silence of
your consciousness if yours wants
to talk to you very carefully
turn it on and begin
so the last stage we will also
respond to noise as a trace but if your mind
tries to talk to you we
will not fight with it
let it talk but do not listen to
it
this is the warmest state of mind
we respond to noise respond our thoughts
if new thoughts appear like clouds
in the sky let them just float do not
try to stop them because an
attempt to stop a war against and type
contributed also create noise and begin
[music]
now imagine the sky above the ocean that
from this sky a beautiful
picture appears the image is one of the teachers of your
life and he descends from the sky sitting on a
beautiful flower it can be a lotus or a
rose but it is a very, very beautiful flower
choose one of the teachers of your life
we ​​are all lucky we have many
different teachers we have parents mom and
dad we have teachers at school
[music]
Mars maybe you had a
sports coach and a music teacher a teacher
and an art teacher and later in
our lives we met people who
taught us how to work and then our lives
appear  Husbands, wives, and children,
who are also teachers for
many of us, we have spiritual teachers in
churches or mosques or in the blue Goga,
and we all have historical
teachers such as Sos Muhammad,
so choose one of them, you have a
large choice, and ask the teacher to come
to you, sitting on this beautiful
flower through the sky, come and sit
opposite you, you are both in the sky, and
ask
and join your meditation for a
few minutes, and ask them for a
blessing for your mind and for
your meditation. We will sit next to
your teacher in silence for a few
minutes, and then we will finish for today,
so try to focus on
these last few minutes,
enjoy that the teacher is
with you, and enjoy this silence. Let's
begin.
[music]
Now we will take three deep breaths. I was amazed.
Don't open your eyes. Not
today. We made a lot of good karma. A
series of meditations is such direct, raw
good karma. Let's share this
karma with other people. I filed Hari in
Mexico, throughout the country, and throughout the world.
[music]
Three lengths.  exhale exhale good
karma
share it with the world
[music]
now slowly open your eyes I
like to stretch your arms a little do
this stretch
please drink a lot of water
bring water here and drink and we
will take a break in 15 minutes I thought
if you have any questions they could
be about meditation they can on any
topic you have a microphone
but okay you just need to ask the
question very loudly me and seiji we will
repeat the question any questions don't be
modest don't be shy it seems to me these
seeds he they are we have them on their own
[music]
recently I was
I was we were with our other who
was giving birth and my question and my question
why should women go through
such pain during contractions
okay great question they say
that when a
great person is born how will they be they don't
cause any pain to their own from their
mother his mother held onto a tree like that
when she gave birth to him
her name was Maya and you just popped out
and
from them she didn't have any
pain
they say they say if we are not yet not the
best people yet when we
are born we cause pain  For our
mothers, this is also our past food,
of course you can, of course you can't
harm others
if they don't have the appropriate seeds, and
then they say that truly good
people are born in the middle of a lotus
[music]
there is such a famous sign, you have a child,
and there is a famous saint
who was born in the middle of a lotus, and this is
yoga, yoga sutra, yoga Patanjali, and
she simply poured a flower onto the lotus
and it just fell, that's a roll, that means
it will just appear and fall in the
middle of the queue.  and here is pad Angela, so
amazingly, the threat of Jesus was also
born in such a miraculous way
and in the sutra of the diamond cutter, and it speaks
of four ways of birth, called
Kenya, the first kind is called Konki
[music]
born from an egg
like birds, sometimes they are called 2g,
born twice, twice, why does the
egg appear first, this is the first time, and then the
egg splits, this is the second time, this is the second kind of
birth, then birth from the womb
brings a lot of pain to both the mother and the
child because of bad seeds in both
mothers in the child and then dutiki,
this means a miraculous birth like Jesus and
like Buddha without bringing any more
material, these are the four types of birth, and
recently I was
forgotten, and someone told me that their father
died
and they asked me for help
[music]
I sent the MSC that my
teacher wrote about how when people die and
people asked him questions and he
answered them about how people die and in
that with and what was written about 23
years ago, he says by the way,
despite the fact that these are bad seeds
that bring pain to the mother when
birth to
give birth to the
operator's child is very
concentrated good seeds,
therefore, giving life to another living
being is considered almost
countless good seeds, cool,
you choose Anatoly, the night passed and you
talked in
you talked about the vision that
occurs to a person after a direct
split of emptiness,
they see all living beings, of which there is an
infinite number, you talked about this
very briefly
once in one study you talked about
this in more detail at the end of this teaching you
said something shocking, you said
that you see every face, an infinite
number of beings, the face of each being
and you said that there is an infinite number of them
and I wanted to ask how this relates to
emptiness, well,
let's talk about this when you
see the trade wind directly, what happens
physically and you know because and you know
because you are such a great yoga teacher,
all your channels open, all the nodes
go away. There are 17,000 17 channels and the three
main ones and the middle channel never
opens completely when you die,
it opens for a short time, just
for a few seconds, and when you
experience orgasm during sex,
it opens completely for just a
few seconds and some say
sex should be a good method for
opening channels,
this is normal, but the next moment
After orgasm, this channel closes even more
tightly,
maybe that's why your husband
falls asleep and this method is not very
long-lasting, the deep meaning of why we
do yoga is to open that same
middle channel and make it
stay open if you open it
wide enough you will see emptiness and there
is a high statement
canon canon
[music]
gave her word to help you can
emptiness you can see emptiness in two
ways well three ways and an external
internal method is meditation and the
study of two husbands in the kitchen and an external
method to manipulate your channels
with the help of yoga it can also be
swimming any good exercise
and combinations of these methods are very
powerful on the day when you
see meditation directly this
central channel opens completely
and it remains open for
about 24 hours completely open in the
first 20 minutes you see emptiness
directly and went as you go out test about
meditation the channel is still open and it
begins to slowly close not like
after sex and this will continue until
your date as you go to
bed this is about 10 12 hours
during this time your mind is free
you begin to see things that you
usually you don't see
one of the interesting things is that you
can read other people's thoughts
until the end of that day it's a very
strange feeling
and of course the most wonderful thing is with your
eyes open and you no longer
meditate on emptiness you begin
to see faces one after another and it
feels like
Stanley took me to a pool in a hotel in
China
I thought I thought it would be cool to combine
with yoga but I quickly get goosebumps
and I started looking for an indoor pool I'm looking for an
indoor pool an indoor pool near
my house and there with the account as it is
located in a casino
[music]
I was a casino
once in my life with my father and
also you are not allowed to pay for
what you swim there I asked the
hotel manager for a meeting I have many friends
in China and I like and like the gamba game
and I like to bet if you do
n't let me swim in the pool
for free I will prepare an advertisement for your
casino for them they sent well okay I
swam there for about a year and they forgot not to
ask to do any advertising for their
casino and I reminded me of this but
this is also on  In fact, it's very sad and
the place is owned by an
American and according to their law you
can smoke inside the building and the entire
casino is covered in this
smoke cigarette smoke except for the pool and
[music]
very grown old people are playing
these slot machines and their faces are also
like this smoke coating while
this is very sad and when they
start this machine and the
drum starts spinning and when
for example you knock out 3 and it doesn't hit then they
start winning so why am I talking about this
and during your meditation faces
start appearing like
this slot machine on this slot
machine like these cherries
and you don't know what's happening like a question
you watch this
your mother's face appears then you think and you have
such a natural reaction to all this
mom I love you I will take care of you
don't worry I will you will be
forgotten and then the slot machines start
moving again and we drink
your dad's face appears dad you don't worry either I will
take care of you too
and your and your brother appears and all
your whole movie family starts appearing and
all the people you knew at school or at
work start appearing in front  you
one after another and then
people you don't know start falling
and you start saying don't worry I'll take
care of you too don't worry I'll
take care of you too
and it all starts speeding up and then an
animal starts appearing you
finish
all 7 people or they become stupid one by one
and then you move on to animals first
your pets appear your
cat all the mice you caught
during the retreat
I'll take care of you too don't worry I do
n't know about your tricks this one does
but during my three year retreat
I spent a lot of time watching
ants it was my TV every
ant appears and benefits I'll
take care of you too birds and fish you finish
with all the animals I think this figure is somewhere around
100 billion animals and then you
start seeing the faces of people from other
planets
it speeds up and speeds up
time also comes from your seeds
within 20 minutes you see every living
creature in the entire universe and you say
I'll take care of you too don't worry I
think and I think this is called aria
Bodhisattva
and they had this experience directly, the experience of
wanting to help every living being, and
they saw emptiness directly, they saw
emptiness directly before, when they
saw it directly after, it opened their
central channel, that's why we
do yoga
and because the channel is not yet
loaded, it will close by the evening, by the time
you go to bed, it will already be
closed,
they can see all these beings
directly, and this is the connection between seeing
emptiness directly and the experience of bodhichitta
in wine, and in addition, what I wanted to
tell you is that it is very difficult to have a
bad day after this
experience, it is possible, it
happens to you, it happens when you
feel sad when things go
wrong somehow, but in general, it is almost
impossible to be unhappy after this
experience because a great purpose appears in your life,
this is a very beautiful experience, and
let's take a break, this is good, tires,
and I will answer your questions.